twip.org 2012-09-20

# Privacy Policy - The World In Photos: Wiki

## Privacy Policy

[Back home](http://wiki.twip.org/) :: last edited by sim100 (April 30, 2009, 17:58:24)

**Overall privacy statement**  
We take your privacy seriously. Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we want to help you understand the terms and conditions surrounding the collection and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses the types of information we gather, how we use it, and how to correct or change it. These privacy practices apply to the Web site and its properties and services that you were viewing when you clicked through to this policy, which is operated directly by us, by our partner, or by our affiliate. Please note that by using the services or web site, you agree that any information you provide to us will be stored in the United States in accordance with this Privacy Policy and United States law.

**1\. What information does TWIP collect?**  
Our primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you with the best and most useful content and services. Several of the services and features that we offer on our sites require you to provide us with information as a condition of usage. These include access to subscription-only areas, the ability to post pictures, participation in sweepstakes or contests and subscriptions to email newsletters.

We collect personally identifiable information, such as your username, password, email address, country of residence, gender and date of birth when you provide it to us.

Once you register with TWIP you are less anonymous to us.

**2\. What is TWIP practice regarding cookies?**  
Your Internet browser has a feature called cookies, which stores small amounts of data on your computer about your visit to any of our sites. You do not need to have cookies turned on to visit most of our sites, although active participation in certain areas of our sites may require cookies. Cookies alone tell us nothing about who you are unless you specifically give us personally identifiable information, in which case we use the information to enhance your services in the ways described below. By adjusting your settings on your browser, you may elect not to allow cookies to be collected.

We allow other companies that are presenting advertisements on our sites and, sometimes, in our newsletters to use tracking technology on your computer. We do not give any personally identifiable information to them as part of this relationship. Unless you visit the Web site of these companies and provide them with personally identifiable information about yourself, these tracking technologies tell those advertisers nothing about who you are. Our advertisers' use of tracking technology is subject to their own privacy policies.

Note: about Google Advertising on this website: Google use cookies for its Adsense program and to publish ads on TWIP. The Dart cookies used by Google allow them to adapt the ad publishing based on internet users behavior. Internet users have the possibility to desactivate Dart cookies. More info here: <http://www.google.com/privacy_ads>

**3\. How does TWIP use the information?**  
We use the information we gather for four general purposes:

  1. customize the advertising and the content you see;
  2. To enhance the user experience in our network of sites and software applications; We use tracking information to determine how well each page performs overall based on aggregate user demographics and traffic patterns to those pages. This helps us continue to build a better service for you;
  3. To fulfill your requests for certain products and services, such as sending out electronic newsletters and enabling you to participate in paid services, polls, contests, and message boards;
  4. To send you information you agreed to receive about topics we think will be of interest to you.

**4\. How does TWIP share the information?**  
_Personally identifiable information_  
We will make your personally identifiable information available to other companies or people when:

  1. You have elected to allow us to share that information at the time that you registered with us or provided us the information, or through a subsequent affirmative election through our website(s) or software applications.
  2. You are the winner of a contest or a sweepstakes that is co-sponsored with a third party and that third party needs your information in order to manage the prize fulfillment process.
  3. When required by law, such as when we respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process.
  4. We believe that your actions violate applicable laws, TWIP’s Terms of Use, or any usage guidelines for specific products or services, or threaten the rights, property, or safety of our company, our users, or others.

_Aggregate information_  
We aggregate personally identifiable information and disclose such information in a non-personally identifiable manner to advertisers and other third parties for marketing, promotional, and other purposes. We do not disclose to these entities any information that could be used to identify you personally.

_Business transfers_  
We are always seeking to improve our network of Web sites and our business. In accomplishing these objectives, we may buy or sell a company, or one or more of the companies in our corporate family may merge with or be acquired by another company. If we sell a business, we may transfer some or all of your information as a part of the sale in order that the service being provided to you may continue or for other business purposes.

**5\. What are my options?**  
Users who would rather not provide any of the user data requested by our registration process do not need to register with us. You can still view much of the content and use many of the services offered by our sites without registering.

We also give users the following options:

  1. Opting not to receive our electronic newsletters or those of third parties when registering. Users who opt in may remove themselves from mailing lists at any time through the subscription-management pages, my account pages, or by following the instructions at the end of the e-mail they received from us. Please note, however, that we reserve the right to send you email about the administration of your account, policy changes, legal, billing, and other matters that will affect your use of the web site. These communications are mandatory.
  2. Opting not to provide certain personal information when registering for a site or software application, provided, however, that you may not be able to use some of our products or services without providing us with certain information.

**6\. How can I review and update my personally identifiable information?**  
You can review, correct, or change the information collected during registration for TWIP here: http://www.twip.org/my_account.php  
The instructions for doing this can be found in our member-services areas or in the footer links available on all sites. Users may change information at any time and as often as necessary. Users who are experiencing problems with our services or who have questions about how our services work can contact us using e-mail addresses at the bottom of this page.

**7\. How will I know if the privacy policy is changed?**  
Any modifications to our privacy practices will be reflected first in this Privacy Policy. If there is a material change in our privacy practices, we will indicate on our sites that our privacy practices have changed and provide a link to the new privacy statement. If we are going to be using the information collected from users in a manner materially different from that stated at the time of collection, we will send affected users written notice of the change by e-mail.

**Questions, Comments**  
Questions regarding this privacy statement or any other aspects of our website should be sent by email to info at twip dot org. 

* * *

**You like this post? Share it!**
